Ted Hughes papers, 1940-1999
Emory University
- Subject files, circa 1966-1995, Series 5; Boxes 155-171
  - Arts Council of Great Britain; Firetake Productions (Box 155, Folder 5)
  - Arts Council of Great Britain Anthology; Menard Press (Box 155, Folder 6)
  - Arts for Nature Trust (Box 155, Folder 7)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1970-1979 (Box 155, Folder 8)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1970-1979 (Box 155, Folder 9)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1980-1983 (Box 155, Folder 10)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1980 Poetry Competition (Box 155, Folder 11)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1980 Poetry Competition (Box 155, Folder 12)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1982 Poetry Competition (Box 155, Folder 13)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1982 Poetry Competition (Box 156, Folder 1)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1982 Poetry Competition Anthology (Box 156, Folder 2)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1984-1986 (Box 156, Folder 3)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1984-1986 (Box 156, Folder 4)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1984-1986 (Box 156, Folder 5)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1984 Poetry Competition (Box 156, Folder 6)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1984 Poetry Competition (Box 156, Folder 7)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1984 Poetry Competition (Box 156, Folder 8)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1990-1991 (Box 156, Folder 9)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1990-1991 (Box 157, Folder 1)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1990-1991 (Box 157, Folder 2)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1992-1993 (Box 157, Folder 3)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1992-1993 (Box 157, Folder 4)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1994-1995 (Box 157, Folder 5)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1994-1995 (Box 157, Folder 6)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1994-1995 (Box 157, Folder 7)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1995-1996 (Box 158, Folder 1)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1995-1996 (Box 158, Folder 2)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1995-1996 (Box 158, Folder 3)
  - Arvon Foundation: 1996; Leverhulme Trust (Box 158, Folder 4)
  - Arvon Foundation: Public Relations Materials (Box 158, Folder 5)
  - Arvon Foundation: Interviews with Ted Hughes [See also Subseries 2.2: Gaudete TS and MS summary of plot for shortened reading with corrections] (Box 158, Folder 6)
  - Arvon Foundation: Interview Corrections (Box 158, Folder 7)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: 1978-1984 (Box 158, Folder 8)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: 1978-1984 (Box 158, Folder 9)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: 1978-1984 (Box 158, Folder 10)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: 1984-1985 (Box 158, Folder 11)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: 1987 Job applications (Box 156, Folder 1)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: 1987 Job applications (Box 159, Folder 2)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: 1987 Job applications (Box 159, Folder 3)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: 1987 Job applications (Box 159, Folder 4)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: Leases (Box 159, Folder 5)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: Bills (Box 159, Folder 6)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: Bills (Box 159, Folder 7)
  - Arvon Foundation at Lumb Bank: Bills (Box 159, Folder 8)
  - Arvon Foundation at Totleigh Barton: 1977-1983 (Box 159, Folder 9)
  - Arvon Foundation at Totleigh Barton: 1977-1983 (Box 159, Folder 10)
  - Bodley Head (Box 159, Folder 11)
  - Carcanet Press (Box 159, Folder 12)
  - Davids, Roy (Box 159, Folder 13)
  - Drawing of Ted Hughes by Michael Daley (Box 159, Folder 14)
  - Exam (standardized) questions about Hughes works (Box 159, Folder 15)
  - Farming and Wildlife Advisory Group School Competition (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Finances (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - Foster, John (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - Gallery Press, Peter Fallon (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - Government reports on privacy, media intrusion, and press self-regulation (Box 160, Folder 5)
  - Graves, Robert: Memorial (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - Great Ormond Street Children's Hospital (Box 160, Folder 7)
  - Higley, Jeff (Box 160, Folder 8)
  - Interview with TH for Paris Review, 1994 (corrections by TH) (Box 160, Folder 9)
  - IOU Theatre (Box 160, Folder 10)
  - Iron Man Productions: Correspondence 1985-1990 (Box 160, Folder 11)
  - Iron Man Productions: Correspondence re Warner Brothers proposal (Box 160, Folder 12)
  - Iron Man Productions: Correspondence re opera and screen-play (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Iron Man Productions: Correspondence re Young VIC Production (Box 161, Folder 2)
  - Iron Man Productions: Correspondence re future productions (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - Iron Man Productions: License and extension agreement (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Iron Man Productions: Newspaper clippings (Box 161, Folder 5)
  - Iron Man Productions: Publicity (Box 161, Folder 6)
  - Iron Man Productions: Script (Box 161, Folder 7)
  - Iron Man Productions: Requests for productions (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - Iron Man Productions: Warner Brothers proposal (Box 161, Folder 9)
  - James and James (Box 161, Folder 10)
  - Letters of Support (Box 161, Folder 11)
  - Lists-Contents of boxes, folders for shipping (Box 161, Folder 12)
  - Lists-Magazine Submissions [some in Sylvia Plath's hand] (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Lists-Miscellaneous (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Lists-"Organization of Trunk" (Box 162, Folder 3)
  - Lists-To-Do (Box 162, Folder 4)
  - London Academy of Music and Dramatic Art (Box 162, Folder 5)
  - London Academy of Music and Dramatic Art (Box 162, Folder 6)
  - Menard Press (Box 162, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 162, Folder 8)
  - Moniack Trust (Box 162, Folder 9)
  - Napier, Priscilla (Box 162, Folder 10)
  - Napier, Priscilla (Box 162, Folder 11)
  - Pavilion Press (Box 162, Folder 12)
  - Plath Notes (Box 162, Folder 13)
  - Poetry Book Society (Box 162, Folder 14)
  - The Poetry Catalogue (Box 162, Folder 15)
  - Poetry International Festival: 1967 (Box 162, Folder 16)
  - Poets Reading Their Work: Tel Aviv, Israel 1971 (Box 163, Folder 1)
  - Puffin, Viking, Kestrel (Box 163, Folder 2)
  - Rafferty, Sean (Box 163, Folder 3)
  - Rafferty, Sean (Box 163, Folder 4)
  - Reading Tour: Isle of Wight, 1980 (Box 163, Folder 5)
  - Reading Tour: 1984; Correspondence (Box 163, Folder 6)
  - Reading Tour: Bologna, Italy, 1994 (Box 163, Folder 7)
  - Reading Tour: Bologna, Italy, 1994 (Box 163, Folder 8)
  - Reed Publishing (Box 163, Folder 9)
  - Rhino Rescue (Box 164, Folder 1)
  - Rhino Rescue (Box 164, Folder 2)
  - Rhino Rescue (Box 164, Folder 3)
  - River Conservation: Atlantic Salmon Trust (Box 164, Folder 4)
  - River Conservation: National Rivers Association (Box 164, Folder 5)
  - River Conservation: National Rivers Association (Box 164, Folder 6)
  - River Conservation: National Rivers Association (Box 164, Folder 7)
  - River Conservation: National Rivers Association (Box 165, Folder 1)
  - River Conservation: National Rivers Association (Box 165, Folder 2)
  - River Conservation: The Salmon and Trout Association (Box 165, Folder 3)
  - River Conservation: Wild Steelhead Campaign (Box 165, Folder 4)
  - River Conservation (Box 165, Folder 5)
  - River Conservation (Box 165, Folder 6)
  - River Conservation (Box 165, Folder 7)
  - River Conservation (Box 166, Folder 1)
  - River Conservation (Box 166, Folder 2)
  - The Rougemount Press (Box 166, Folder 3)
  - Sacred Earth Drama Trust (Box 166, Folder 4)
  - Sacred Earth Drama Trust (Box 166, Folder 5)
  - Sacred Earth Drama Trust (Box 166, Folder 6)
  - Sacred Earth Drama Trust (Box 166, Folder 7)
  - The Scolar Press (Box 166, Folder 8)
  - Second Asian Poetry Festival: Bangladesh, 1989 (Box 167, Folder 1)
  - Second Asian Poetry Festival: Bangladesh, 1989 (Box 167, Folder 2)
  - Second Asian Poetry Festival: Bangladesh, 1989 (Box 167, Folder 3)
  - Second Asian Poetry Festival: Bangladesh, 1989 (Box 167, Folder 4)
  - Shakespeare Globe Centre (Box 167, Folder 5)
  - Southwest Arts and The Arts Council of Great Britain (Box 167, Folder 6)
  - Southwest Arts and The Arts Council of Great Britain (Box 167, Folder 7)
  - Sunlaws House Hotel (Box 167, Folder 8)
  - Torridge River: Articles about (Box 168, Folder 1)
  - Torridge River: Bideford Action Group Agenda (Box 168, Folder 2)
  - Torridge River: Correspondence 1983-1984 (Box 168, Folder 3)
  - Torridge River: Correspondence 1985 (Box 168, Folder 4)
  - Torridge River: Correspondence 1986-1988 (Box 168, Folder 5)
  - Torridge River: Correspondence n.d (Box 168, Folder 6`)
  - Torridge River: TH Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 168, Folder 7)
  - Torridge River: TH Correspondence, undated (Box 168, Folder 8)
  - Torridge River: TH Correspondence and Manuscripts (Box 168, Folder 9)
  - Torridge River: Correspondence Notes (Box 168, Folder 10)
  - Torridge River: Fishing Regulations (various) (Box 168, Folder 11)
  - Torridge River: Fundraising (Box 168, Folder 12)
  - Torridge River: Legal Proceedings-Bideford-Fine Screening Public Inquiry (Box 168, Folder 13)
  - Torridge River: Legal Proceedings-Ian Cook v. South West Water PLC (Box 168, Folder 14)
  - Torridge River: Legal Proceedings-Water Act of 1973 and Pollution Control Act of 1974 (Box 168, Folder 15)
  - Torridge River: Membership Applications (Box 169, Folder 1)
  - Torridge River: Misc. Published Works (Box 169, Folder 2)
  - Torridge River: Newspaper Clippings (Box 169, Folder 3)
  - Torridge River: Poetry Competition (Box 169, Folder 4)
  - Torridge River: Proposals (Proposal for smolt farm) (Box 169, Folder 5)
  - Torridge River: Reports (Box 169, Folder 6)
  - Torridge River: River Taw Fisheries Association (Box 169, Folder 7)
  - Torridge River: River Torridge Fisheries Association (Box 169, Folder 8)
  - Torridge River: South West Rivers Association (Box 169, Folder 9)
  - Torridge River: South West Rivers Association (Box 169, Folder 10)
  - Torridge River: Summary (Box 169, Folder 11)
  - Torridge River: Summary (Box 169, Folder 12)
  - Torridge River: Taw and Torridge Joint Consultative Committee (Box 169, Folder 13)
  - Torridge River: Torridge Action Group-Summary of Issues (Box 170, Folder 1)
  - Torridge River: Writings-"The Ballad of Bideford" (Box 170, Folder 2)
  - Thames Television; The English Programme (Box 170, Folder 3)
  - Ulanova, Galina, MS horoscope and biographical notes (Box 170, Folder 4)
  - University of Aberdeen: 1990 Honorary Degree (Box 170, Folder 5)
  - University of Sheffield: 1990 Honorary Degree (Box 170, Folder 6)
  - W.H. Smith Young Writer's Competition (Box 170, Folder 7)
  - W.H. Smith Young Writer's Competition: Anthology (Box 170, Folder 8)
  - W.H. Smith and Ilkley Literature Festival: Correspondence 1980-1983 (Box 170, Folder 9)
  - W.H. Smith and The Children's Literacy Competition (Box 170, Folder 10)
  - West Country Television (Box 170, Folder 11)
  - West Country Television (Box 170, Folder 12)
  - West Devon Schools Anthology (Box 171, Folder 1)
  - West Devon Schools Anthology (Box 171, Folder 2)
  - Windfarms (Box 171, Folder 3)
  - Wordsworth Trust (Box 171, Folder 4)
  - The World Wildlife Fund: Environmental Poetry Competition (Box 171, Folder 5)
  - Writer's Action Group (Box 171, Folder 6)
  - Writer's Action Group (Box 171, Folder 7)
  - Viking Penguin Press (Box 171, Folder 8)
  - Yacht (Box 171, Folder 9)
  - Young Observer National Children's Poetry Competition (Box 171, Folder 10)
- Printed material, 1955-1999, Series 6; Boxes 172-176; OP61-101, 109-114
  Published material that has been collected by Hughes is represented in this printed material series, which contains texts by Hughes, texts about Hughes' work, and texts by others about various issues of interest to Hughes. In most cases, descriptions of individually listed items note the date and source of publication.
  Published works by Hughes are collected under one subseries arranged chronologically by publication date. Printed material about Hughes is gathered in a distinct subseries that is further divided into three subsections: articles, clippings, promotional material for his work, including documents relating to readings. The third subseries contains reviews about Hughes books including poetry, plays, and audio productions.
  The final subseries consists of two s. The first scrapbook contains clippings of Ted Hughes' poems and other writings, reviews of his work, and some letters from 1956-1963. The second scrapbook contains clippings of Hughes's and Sylvia Plath's poems and other writings, reviews of their works, and other press notices from 1963-1968.
  Organized into four subseries: (6.1) Writings by Ted Hughes, (6.2) Writings about Ted Hughes, (6.3) Reviews, and (6.4) Scrapbooks.
  Special restrictions apply: Due to the fragile nature of the Blue scrapbook, 1956-1963 (OP103) in Subseries 6.4, researchers are required to use the photocopy of the original.
  - Writings by Ted Hughes, 1955-1996, Subseries 6.1; Boxes 172-173; OP61-88
    The subseries consists of published writings by Ted Hughes from 1955-1996. The writings include individual poems published in periodical and newspapers.
    - "'The woman with such high heels,'" Delta, Spring 1955 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - "Billy Hook and Three Souvenirs," Jack and Jill, July 1958 (2 photocopies) (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - May 1956-January 1962 (Box 172, Folder 3)
    - "Still Life," The London Magazine, vol. 1 no. 11, February 1962 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - March 1962-December 1962 (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - January 1963-October 1964 (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - "O White Elite Lotus," Critical Quarterly, vol. 6 no. 4, winter 1964 (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - "Dice," Critical Quarterly, summer 1964 (Box 172, Folder 8)
    - "After Lorca," New Poetry 1964: Critical Quarterly Supplement no. 5, [Autumn 1964] (Box 172, Folder 9)
    - January 1965-October 1966 (Box 172, Folder 10)
    - "Warm Moors," "Stations," The Knight," "Folklore," A Match," Critical Quarterly, vol. 8 no. 1, spring 1966 (Box 172, Folder 11)
    - "Skylarks," Critical Quarterly, vol. 8 no. 3, autumn 1966 (Box 172, Folder 12)
    - "Notes on the Chronological Order of Sylvia Plath's Poems," Tri-Quarterly, no. 7, fall 1966 (Box 172, Folder 13)
    - "Public Speech" and "A Wind Flashes the Grass," Critical Quarterly, vol. 8 no. 4, winter 1966 (Box 172, Folder 14)
    - "Reveille," New Poems 1966: Critical Poetry Supplement no. 7, [autumn 1966] (Box 172, Folder 15)
    - "Vasco Popa," Tri-Quarterly, no. 9, Spring 1967 (Box 172, Folder 16)
    - November 1966-Sept. 28, 1967 (Box 172, Folder 17)
    - "TV On," The Listener, September 28, 1967 (Box 172, Folder 18)
    - October 19, 1967-November 30, 1967 (Box 172, Folder 19)
    - "A Battle," Outposts, no. 74, autumn 1967 (Box 172, Folder 20)
    - "Ghost Crabs" and "The Bear," Poetry 1967: Critical Quarterly Supplement no. 8 (Box 172, Folder 21)
    - January 25, 1968-September 26, 1968 (Box 172, Folder 22)
    - "Thought Fox," "An Otter," "Thrushes," "Relic," and "Piboch," Four: Critical Quarterly Supplement no. 9 (Box 172, Folder 23)
    - January 2, 1969-July 24, 1969 (Box 172, Folder 24)
    - "Second Bedtime Story" and "Notes for a Little Play," Poetry 1969: Critical Quarterly Supplement no.10 (Box 172, Folder 25)
    - "Crow's Songs of Himself," "Conjuring in Heaven," "Crow and the Stone," "Crow Sickened," "Song of Woe," and "Crow Blacker Than Ever," Critical Quarterly, vol. 12 no. 2, summer 1970 (Box 172, Folder 26)
    - "Owl's Song," "Crow Alights," and "Crow's Song of Himself," Poetry 1970: Critical Quarterly Supplement no.11 (Box 172, Folder 27)
    - "This Game of Chess is Played for Love" (2), ca. 1970, Christmas card with three Elizabeth Frank heads, done for Peter Marsh (one signed, "and from Ted Hughes every year") [accessions 90-11-09 and 87-01-10] (Box 172, Folder 28)
    - February 1970-April 15, 1971 (Box 172, Folder 29)
    - "Orghast: Talking Without Words," Vogue, December 1971 (Box 172, Folder 30)
    - Autumn 1972-May 30 1975 (Box 172, Folder 31)
    - "Scream," Stand, 1975/1976 (Box 172, Folder 32)
    - "Feburary 17th," Bananas, no.5, summer 1976 (Box OP61)
    - "From Gaudete," Bananas, no.6, autumn/winter 1976 (Box OP62)
    - "Northerly Airs" [includes "Open to Huge Light," "The Sluttiest Sheep in England," "When Men Got to the Summit," "Walls," "Heptonstall Old Church," "Mill Ruins," and "Lumb Chimneys"], The Observer, 20 May 1979 (Box 172, Folder 33)
    - February 12, 1976-January 13, 1983 (Box 172, Folder 34)
    - "Eagle"and "Low Water," London Review of Books, vol. 2 no. 19, Oct. 2-Oct. 15, 1980 (Box OP63)
    - "Nymet," London Review of Books, vol. 2 no. 23, December 4-December 17, 1980 (Box OP64)
    - "An October Salmon," London Review of Books, vol. 3 no. 7, April 16, 1981-May 6, 1981 (Box OP65)
    - "That Morning," London Review of Books, vol. 3 no. 22/23, December 3-December 16, 1981 (Box OP66)
    - "Sing the Rat," London Review of Books, vol. 4 no. 3, February 18-March 3, 1982 (Box OP67)
    - "Remembering Teheran," London Review of Books, vol. 4 no. 15, August 19-Sept. 1, 1982 (Box OP68)
    - "The Great Irish Pike," London Review of Books, vol. 4 no. 22/23, December 2-December 29, 1982 (Box OP69)
    - "A Sparrow-hawk," London Review of Books, vol. 5 no. 5, March 17-March 31, 1983 (Box OP70)
    - "Swallows," The Listener, April 23, 1983 (Box 172, Folder 35)
    - "Honey Bee," The Listener, May 12, 1983 (Box 173, Folder 1)
    - "The Gulkana," London Review of Books, vol. 5 no. 9, May 19-June 1, 1983 (Box OP71)
    - "Evening Thrush," The Listener, June 2, 1983 (Box 173, Folder 2)
    - "Madfly," "August Salmon," "An Eel," "Pigeon's Wings," and "August Evening," London Magazine, vol. 23 no. 7, October 1983 (Box 173, Folder 3)
    - November 25, 1983-May 7, 1984 (Box 173, Folder 4)
    - "Daffodils," London Review of Books, vol. 6 no. 4, March 1-March 14, 1984 (Box OP72)
    - "Walt" and "A Macaw," London Review of Books, vol. 6 no. 21, November 15-December 5, 1984 (Box OP73)
    - "Sacrifice," London Review of Books, vol.7 no. 1, January 24, 1985 (Box OP74)
    - "The Angel," Twelve times a Yea r, January/February 1985 (Box 173, Folder 5)
    - "Conscripts," South West Review, no. 24, February 1985 (Box 173, Folder 6)
    - "Three Voices," The Spectator, February 2, 1985 (Box 173, Folder 7)
    - "Slump Sundays," The Times Literary Supplement, March 8, 1985 (Box OP75)
    - "Remembering Jenny Rankin," The Rialto, spring 1985 (Box 173, Folder 8)
    - "For the Duration," The Listener, May 9, 1985 (Box 173, Folder 9)
    - "Cuckoo" and "Where I Sit Writing My Letter," The Listener, June13, 1985 (Box 173, Folder 10)
    - August 13, 1985-October 1989 (Box 173, Folder 11)
    - "Grouse Butts," The Listener, August 15, 1985 (Box 173, Folder 12)
    - "Edith," The Listener, September 5, 1985 (Box 173, Folder 13)
    - "Rights," The Artful Reporter, no. 82 October 1985 (Box OP76)
    - "Telegraph Wires," The Listener, November 12, 1985 (Box 173, Folder 14)
    - "Manchester Skytrain," London Review of Books, vol. 8 no. 4, March 6, 1986 (Box OP77)
    - "The Crown of the Kingdom," The Times, April 21, 1986 (Box OP78)
    - "The Pike," "Mayday" The Listener, May 22, 1986 (Box 173, Folder 15)
    - "First Things First," The Times, June 4, 1987 (Box OP79)
    - "Climbing into Heptonstall," London Review of Books, vol. 8 no. 11, June 19, 1986 (Box OP80)
    - "Poetry Explained," The Listener, June 26, 1986 (Box 173, Folder 16)
    - "On the Brink," The Daily Telegraph Weekend, October 24, 1987 (Box OP81)
    - "High Water," Scottish Wildlife, winter 1987/1988 (Box 173, Folder 17)
    - "Glimpse," London Review of Books, vol. 10 no. 3, February 4, 1988 (Box OP82)
    - "On the Reservations," London Review of Books, vol.10 no. 11, June 2, 1988 (Box OP83)
    - "The Trunk," The Daily Telegraph: The Great British Summer, August 1988 (Box OP84)
    - "Take What You Want But Pay for It," London Review of Books, vol. 10 no. 17, September 29, 1988 (Box OP85)
    - "How God Got His Golden Head," The Duncan Lawrie Journal, summer 1989 (Box 173, Folder 18)
    - "Curlews Lift," "Where I Sit Writing My Letter," "A Dove," "Tern," and "The Unknown Wren," Birds Magazine, summer 1989 (Box 173, Folder 19)
    - "Three Voices for the Queen Mother," The Daily Telegraph Weekend, August 4, 1990 (Box OP86)
    - "The Fortieth Anniversary of the Accession of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II," Daily Telegraph, February 6, 1992 [photocopy] (Box 173, Folder 20)
    - March 20, 1992 (Box 173, Folder 21)
    - "Ode to the Organism," Book Seller, May 13, 1994 (Box 173, Folder 22)
    - "Salmacis and Hermaphroditus" (proof photocopy and published version), New Statesman and Society, June 17, 1994 (Box 173, Folder 23)
    - February 26, 1995 (Box 173, Folder 24)
    - "The Error," The New Yorker, July 3, 1995 (Box 173, Folder 25)
    - "The Oak Tree," The Daily Telegraph, August 4, 1995 (Box OP87)
    - "What is the Truth," Classroom Choice, issue 2, autumn 1995 (Box 173, Folder 26)
    - "Stephen Spendor: Poet of a Lost Culture," Index on Censorship, January 1996 (Box 173, Folder 27)
    - "The Dogs are Eating Your Mother," Asylum, spring 1996 (Box 173, Folder 28)
    - July 28, 1996 (Box 173, Folder 29)
    - "The Rag Rug," The New Yorker, August 5, 1996 (Box 173, Folder 30)
    - October 10, 1996-December 20, 1996 (Box 173, Folder 31)
    - "Platform One," The Sunday Times Books, November 1996 (Box OP88)
    - Undated: "The Bear," "Bullfinches," "October Dawn," from "Prometheus on his Crag" and "River" (Box 173, Folder 32)
  - Writings about Ted Hughes, 1960-1999, Subseries 6.2; Boxes 174; OP89-99, 109-114
    The subseries consists of published writings about Ted Hughes from 1960-1999. The published writings include articles, clippings, and promotional material. Published reviews of Hughes's works can be found in Subseries 6.3.
    Arranged by record type; then in chronological order.
    - Articles
    - "Stuff Your Pension," Queen, May 25, 1966 (Box 174, Folder 1)
    - "Orghast," by Tom Stoppard, Literary Times Supplement, October 1, 1971 (Box OP89)
    - "The Poetry of Ted Hughes," by P. Strauss, Theoria: A Journal of Studies, May 1972 (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - "Beasts/Shamans/Baskin: The contemporary poem in the 20th century," by David Porter, Boston University Journal, no. 3, 1974 (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - "Ted Hughes", David Porter, American Poetry Review, vol. 4 no. 5, 1975 (Box OP90)
    - "Ted Hughes," extracts from Ted Hughes, October 1979 (Box 174, Folder 4)
    - "Correspondence," Books and Issues, 1979 (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - "Ted Hughes: Poet as Teacher," by Sheila Johnson, Alaska Quarterly Review, Spring 1983 (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - "The Signal Poetry Award," Signal 41, May 1983 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - "Ted Hughes: Dikt," Poesi Magasin, no. 2, 1984 (Box 174, Folder 8)
    - "Poet's Battle Against Pollution," Observer, December 9, 1984 (Box 174, Folder 9)
    - "Unconscious With Listening," Devon Life, June 1985 (Box 174, Folder 10)
    - "Ted Hughes on Tour" Yorkshire Arts, vol. 4 no. 8, October/November 1985 (Box OP97)
    - "Man of the Week: Ted Hughes," Telegraph Sunday Magazine, no. 483, January 26, 1986 (Box 174, Folder 11)
    - "Poet Cornered," The Listener, June 5, 1986 (Box 174, Folder 12)
    - Cover of the London Review of Books, vol. 9 no. 1, January 8, 1987 (Box OP98)
    - "In Conversation with Ted Hughes, Poet Laureat-Rea Lloyd, Artist," North Devon Magazine, autumn 1987 (Box 174, Folder 13)
    - "Ah, Youth: Ted Hughes and Sylvia Plath at Cambridge and After," TS drafts of essay by Lucas Myers; published in Grand Street 4:4, 86-103, Summer 1989 (Box 174, Folder 14)
    - "The Definitions of Reality," Futures, January/February 1994 (Box 174, Folder 15)
    - "Poetry the Wondercrump Way," Books for Keeps, September 1995 (Box 174, Folder 16)
    - Article about TH in [Hands], 8 November 1996, pp. 32-36 (Box 174, Folder 17)
    - "Two Extremes of a Continuum: on Translating Ted Hughes and Charles Tomlinson into Spanish," Forum for Modern Language Studies, vol. 33 no. 1, 1997 (Box 174, Folder 18)
    - "Ted Hughes and Survival," Philip Pacey, n.d. (Box 174, Folder 19)
    - "Ted Hughes: A Memorial," American Poet, Fall 1999 (Box 174, Folder 20)
    - Clippings